Ravijeet Chandra



ravijeet.chandra@gmail.com



+919756848208



linkedin.com/in/ravijeet-chandra-116112142

Summary

Currently Working as a Data Scientist at Secure Meters Ltd. Experienced in performing Data Wrangling, Data visualisation, ETL, applying Machine learning algorithms to deliver meaningful insights, and solve business problems.

Currently open for opportunities in Machine learning field and Data science, having good knowledge of Python, Business intelligence tool, Database, SQL, Machine Learning concepts.

Experience



Data Scientist

Secure Meters Limited

Oct 2019 - Present (1 year 5 months +)

Data collection, processing, cleaning and building a forecasting model using Machine learning concepts such as ANN, Linear regression.

Classification model using CNN ,YOLO, tensorflow.

Software Developer

Secure Meters Limited

Jul 2018 - Oct 2019 (1 year 4 months)

Developed several commissioning tools which included Android app, IOS app, web service and created database for the same to interact with back office.

Graduate Engineer Trainee

Secure Meters Limited

Jan 2018 - Jun 2018 (6 months)

Developed a hybrid Xamarin app which helps the meter installer to perform field related operation.

Education



DIT UNIVERSITY

Bachelor of Technology, Computer Science 2014 - 2018



St. Xavier's High School, Deoghar

Intermediate, PCM 2012 - 2014



St Xavier's High School, Deoghar

Matriculation, Science 2010 - 2012

Licenses & Certifications

Python - HackerRank 52e51d50d425

CutShort Certified Data Science - Basic - CutShort 31956

CutShort Certified Python - Advanced - CutShort 32057

CutShort Certified Machine Learning - Basic - CutShort 32947

Skills

Python (Programming Language) • Data Science • Machine Learning • Extract, Transform, Load (ETL) • Agile Project Management • Agile Methodologies • PostgreSQL • Swift (Programming Language) • Java • C (Programming Language)

Honors & Awards

Python for Data Science - IBM

Jun 2020

https://courses.cognitiveclass.ai/certificates/53b7d570f4cd44efb6202bacf18010f6